KHALED ATMAZ ALSIBAI

Seattle, WA | 206 488 4146 | khaled.alsibai@gmail.com | www.khaled-alsibai.com

SUMMARY

With over 19 years of experience in the fields of software development and information technology, I seek employment as a front-end web developer building web applications, working to resolve technical issues and doing whatever it takes to meet the needs of clients. I am personable, highly motivated, organized, and reliable. I excel individually and on a team.

LIST OF SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, JQuery UI, JSON, Ajax, Bootstrap, Sass, GitHub, BrowserSync, Sublime Text, responsive web development, User experience, web hosting, browser development tools, multimedia design & development, advertising, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Acrobat, macOS, MS Windows, MS Office, computer assembly, computer diagnostics and maintenance, professional photography, studio lighting, image retouching and manipulation, Nikon Capture NX, Final Cut Pro.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2012 - 2015

FOKS/D.S.E

Operations Manager, Design & Photography Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Consulted with clients and fostered communication to provide the best customer service and account management.
- Developed long-term professional relationships with advertising agencies and business owners.
- Worked with creative directors to develop design concepts and artwork.
- Advertised and implemented effective brand exposure campaigns through web and social media platforms.
- Planned photo sessions from initial concept and staffing through final product delivery for advertising agencies and local businesses.
- Handled photography & lighting in-studio and on location.
- Provided professional image editing services, including: retouching, masking, color management, and other image enhancements.
- Interacted with local photographers, event planners, hair stylists, food stylists, and modeling agencies.
- Built and administered the foksch.com website.
- Oversaw the creative team, administration staff and marketing personnel to ensure smooth day-to-day operations.

TOP SKILLS HTML ----------**JavaScript** -----**Bootstrap** -----**JQuery** -----UX ------Multimedia -----**Photography** -----**Studio lighting** -----**Photo editing** -----**Photoshop** -----Illustrator -----**Microsoft Office** ----macOS & MS Windows -----

VOLUNTEERING

Seattle Goodwill Industries
Computer Lab Instructor,
2016

LANGUAGES

Fluent in: Arabic, English

EDUCATION

Aleppo University
Associate's degree, Electrical
and Electronics Engineering

(1993-1995)

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

2003 – 2010 Miraat Information Technology

Multimedia Project Manager Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Led the multimedia design and development team to produce DVD-based projects.
- Utilized Adobe Director, Flash, Photoshop, and Illustrator, Microsoft Access and V12 database engine, INM's Impressario, Print-O-Matic, and Buddy API.
- Directed 3D artists and graphic designers to create interfaces and workflows that ensured the best UX/DX possible.
- Coordinated with media professionals to produce content for the media bank.
- Collaborated with my team to create Flash media used within Director projects.
- Developed and administered the miraat.com website.

2000 - 2003 Bintech Interactive

Multimedia Designer & Developer Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Provided multimedia design and development for multiple CD-based projects.
- Utilized Adobe Director, Flash, Photoshop, and Illustrator, Microsoft Access and V12 database engine.
- Directed 3D artists and graphic designers to create interfaces and workflows that ensured the best UX/DX possible.
- Researched the concept of inter-app communication between Flash and Director, using both applications together to serve project needs.
- Developed an ActiveX object implemented inside of Director projects that enabled Arabic fonts to display and function correctly.
- Enhanced existing scripts and debugged errors.
- Updated and debugged the bintech.com website.

1997 — 2000 LCE

IT Manager & Centura (SQLBase) Software Developer Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Analyzed the company's existing software system.
- Developed new products from the ground up using Centura.
- Created and optimized SQL queries.
- Tested and tuned database code and information.
- Designed and maintained SQL scripts to update and create new reports.
- Implemented server/network maintenance and software installation, set up new workstations and printers, and ensured network stability.
- Met on a regular basis with my team to articulate project scope and expectations and created a monthly report of recommendations for network upgrades and enhancements.
- Provided technical support and hosted monthly workshops and training.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to HTML (Coursera Course Certificates, License 2YU8YLBCD6Y9)
- Introduction to CSS3 (Coursera Course Certificates, License 3WXQJLJ7PHP8)
- Interactivity with JavaScript (Coursera Course Certificates, License 83Z3DQ7C6TXE)
- Advanced Styling with Responsive Design (Coursera Course Certificates, License LA29DX5XS7SQ)
- HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for Web Developers (in progress)
- Web Design for Everyone capstone (in progress)
- Medical Interpreter (Medical Interpreter written exam, WA)